<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Cucumber Blog]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description>
    <link>https://cucumber.io/</link>
    <image>
      <url>https://cucumber.io/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Cucumber Blog</title>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Ghost 2.23 &amp; Cucumber</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 23:53:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cucumber.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Alex Schladebeck on Testing - Cucumber Podcast]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: html--><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/625808718&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>This month on the Cucumber Podcast we sit down with Alex Schladebeck who identifies as a Tester.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SalFreudenberg">Sal Freudenberg</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/tooky">Steve Tooke</a> - co-founders of Cucumber - ask her about her recent keynote appearance at <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> as well as her thoughts on the role of modern testers on agile</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/alex-schladebeck-on-testing/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5ce7bb3658b27b00c085bed0</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 09:47:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/05/alex-cukenfest.png" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: html--><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/625808718&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe><!--kg-card-end: html--><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/05/alex-cukenfest.png" alt="Alex Schladebeck on Testing - Cucumber Podcast"><p>This month on the Cucumber Podcast we sit down with Alex Schladebeck who identifies as a Tester.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SalFreudenberg">Sal Freudenberg</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/tooky">Steve Tooke</a> - co-founders of Cucumber - ask her about her recent keynote appearance at <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> as well as her thoughts on the role of modern testers on agile teams.</p><p>Alex can be found on <a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/alex-schladebeck-on-testing/twitter.com/alex_schl">Twitter</a>. Alex works for <a href="https://www.bredex.de/en/services">Bredex</a> a software consultancy shop based in Germany. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Distilling the Essence Webinar]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>When creating our scenarios, we want to fully describe the desired functionality, but not over-describe it. We want our scenarios to do more than check for correct operation. </p><p>We want to paint a picture of what’s intended that aids understanding by others (or even ourselves) in the future.</p><p>Which</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/distilling-the-essence/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c9b7b77a346fc00cc615104</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 13:39:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/george-dinwiddie-round.png" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/george-dinwiddie-round.png" alt="Distilling the Essence Webinar"><p>When creating our scenarios, we want to fully describe the desired functionality, but not over-describe it. We want our scenarios to do more than check for correct operation. </p><p>We want to paint a picture of what’s intended that aids understanding by others (or even ourselves) in the future.</p><p>Which details should we leave visible, and which should we hide? In this webinar presentation, we will look at ways to distil our scenarios down to their essence and remove distracting incidental details.</p><p>In this webinar recording, George Dinwiddie an experienced BDD writer, practitioner, and enthusiast, gives you some tips for writing scenarios which sing. </p><p>You can watch the recording on our YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-vgM1YiCea8">here</a>.</p><h3 id="upcoming-events">Upcoming events</h3><p>BDD Kickstart London (April 2nd-3rd 2019) - A two-day class on Behaviour-Driven Development. <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">Learn more</a>. </p><p>CukenFest London (April 4th-5th) - Our annual BDD conference for the whole team. <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">Learn more</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CukenFest asks: Bruno Boucard and Thomas Pierrain]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>In the build up to our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> (April 4th-5th 2019), we've taken some time to chat to a few of our workshop leads and speakers about their experiences delivering software and what people will learn attending their session. </p><p>This time we sat down with <a href="https://twitter.com/brunoboucard">Bruno</a></p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/cukenfest-asks-bruno-boucard-and-thomas-pierran/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c98ac14485ee200cc90a90f</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cukenfest]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 11:32:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-0885.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-0885.jpg" alt="CukenFest asks: Bruno Boucard and Thomas Pierrain"><p>In the build up to our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> (April 4th-5th 2019), we've taken some time to chat to a few of our workshop leads and speakers about their experiences delivering software and what people will learn attending their session. </p><p>This time we sat down with <a href="https://twitter.com/brunoboucard">Bruno Boucard</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/tpierrain">Thomas Pierrain</a>. Bruno and Thomas will run a workshop session on <a href="https://www.eventstorming.com/">Event Storming</a> and <a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/example-mapping-introduction/">Example Mapping</a>, two techniques which have come to prominence in the last couple of years which help teams build understanding and explore the different routes to delivering value.</p><h3 id="your-workshop-experience-event-storming-with-example-mapping-will-take-place-on-april-5th-what-can-attendees-expect-to-learn">Your workshop "Experience Event Storming with Example Mapping" will take place on April 5th. What can attendees expect to learn?</h3><p></p><p>Attendees will learn to use two complementary exploration techniques to better understand how to effectively move from the problem space to the solution space. By articulating those two techniques that have already been proven in their respective contexts, we get an incredible way to understand and to share what really matters in a very short time.</p><h3 id="there-s-a-lot-of-cross-over-between-the-bdd-and-ddd-communities-both-have-similar-strategies-of-building-shared-understanding-and-exploring-the-problem-space-in-great-detail-what-drew-you-to-both-communities">There's a lot of cross over between the BDD and DDD communities - both have similar strategies of building shared understanding and exploring the problem space in great detail. What drew you to both communities?</h3><p></p><p>Both communities are interested in the <em>what</em> and the <em>why</em>. Not only the <em>how</em>.</p><p>Building software in stereotypical silos is frustrating. Poor communication between stakeholders leads to limited understanding which results in buggy software. Practices like BDD and DDD allows "eXtreme Programmers" like us to deepen our understanding and deliver value to the business.</p><h3 id="for-someone-who-is-unfamiliar-with-domain-driven-design-what-books-articles-videos-would-you-point-them-to-and-why">For someone who is unfamiliar with Domain-Driven Design what books, articles, videos would you point them to and why?</h3><ul><li>For folks in development roles who want to understand what is DDD and how it can help them in their daily work: <strong>Let’s reboot DDD!</strong> <strong>by Thomas Pierrain and Jérémie Grodziski [<a href=" http://videos.ncrafts.io/video/167722768">link</a>]</strong></li><li>The Blue Book that started everything for DDD: <strong>Domain Driven Design by Eric Evans [<a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Domain-Driven-Design-Tackling-Complexity-Software/dp/0321125215/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=eric+evans&amp;qid=1553162125&amp;s=gateway&amp;sr=8-1">link</a>]</strong></li><li>Probably the best introduction ever to DDD in books: <strong>Patterns, Principles, and Practices of Domain-Driven Design, by Nick Tune and Scott Millet [<a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/patterns-principles-and/9781118714706/ ">link</a>] </strong>and this free leaflet: <strong>Anatomy of DDD by Scott Millett [<a href=" http://samples.leanpub.com/anatomy-of-DDD-sample.pdf">link</a>]</strong></li><li>Alberto Brandolini explaining the Event Storming techniques and how it relates to DDD: <strong>GOTO 2018 50.000 Orange Stickies Later by Alberto Brandolini [<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NGXl1D-KwRI">link</a>]</strong></li></ul><h3 id="both-communities-have-been-strong-for-15-years-what-do-you-think-are-the-main-contributors-to-their-longevity">Both communities have been strong for ~15+ years. What do you think are the main contributors to their longevity?</h3><p>Smart and passionate people who believe that we can't continue to work and produce software like this. I also think for many it's about finding meaning in our work and doing things the right way. </p><p>Event Storming and Example Mapping are two exploration techniques serving business value. Both share the same core concepts of visualisation and conversations. By visualising simple elements, both techniques offer the opportunity to have structured conversations. And its this mixture of a general vision (Event Storming) and a detailed vision (Example Mapping) which strengthens understanding within the team. </p><p>There is definitely no silver bullet, but the secret lies in the diversity of techniques used: Impact Mapping, User Story Mapping are other techniques to discover the unknown serenely.</p><p>Thanks both! Cya in London.</p><p>Thomas and Bruno will run a workshop on Event Storming and Example Mapping at <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest</a> on April 5th. <a href=" http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">Buy your ticket.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CukenFest London - Have you got your ticket yet?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We're now just a few weeks away from <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>, our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference for the whole team. </p><p>Taking place on April 4th-5th, CukenFest is a festival of ideas for BDD enthusiasts. There will be short talks covering the full range of the Behaviour-Driven Development practice - from discovering</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/cukenfest-london-have-you-got-your-ticket/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c9207055500de00cc10f4bd</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 09:33:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1707.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1707.jpg" alt="CukenFest London - Have you got your ticket yet?"><p>We're now just a few weeks away from <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>, our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference for the whole team. </p><p>Taking place on April 4th-5th, CukenFest is a festival of ideas for BDD enthusiasts. There will be short talks covering the full range of the Behaviour-Driven Development practice - from discovering the scope of a story through to turning business rules and examples into working software. The conference intends to inspire and inform you about the latest thinking and provide a shared space for you to exchange ideas with other practitioners. </p><p>We keep things moving on day 1. Talks are just 15 minutes long - no long intros or drawn out points. That gives us time in the day for conversations - some structured others not - and plenty of space and rooms to break out into. Day 2 is less bounded - there's a dedicated workshop track with some amazing coaches and we'll build a whole agenda of talks, discussions and collaborative sessions through open space. Drawing on the experiences of our speakers, the core team behind Cucumber and you, the attendee, we will build a programme which focuses on the biggest problems we want to solve.</p><!--kg-card-begin: image--><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1750.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="CukenFest London - Have you got your ticket yet?"></figure><!--kg-card-end: image--><p>CukenFest isn't a large scale event. It's deliberately small to allow you to meet others, to have your own puzzles heard and debated, and to give you time and space to explore ideas and practices which can help your team. . The conference is a marvellous mix of roles and people who are all enthusiast about building high-quality software. We're super proud to play host.</p><p><a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">Learn more</a> about the line-up and check out our <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">BDD Kickstart class</a> happening just before (now very limited seats). </p><p></p><p></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Lightning talks from CukenFest London 2018]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Towards the end of the first day of <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>, we allow anyone from the audience to take to the stage to give a short, two-minute talk on a topic they think might interest an audience of BDD enthusiasts. It turns out this is always a lot of fun. In</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/lightning-talks-from-cukenfest-london-2018/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c8f9d5e5500de00cc10f487</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cukenfest]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 13:46:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1587.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1587.jpg" alt="Lightning talks from CukenFest London 2018"><p>Towards the end of the first day of <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>, we allow anyone from the audience to take to the stage to give a short, two-minute talk on a topic they think might interest an audience of BDD enthusiasts. It turns out this is always a lot of fun. In 2018 we had some excellent lightning talks including ones about mob programming, getting into tech without a tech background, and how wool can help you solve tricky software problems. In total we had 9 lightning talks, all of which are now on our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrQMyTCtW0DZF7xWCENbMyMc99o1Bap_1">YouTube channel</a>. </p><p>I'm very much looking forward to the lightning talks sessions when CukenFest returns next month. If you haven't got your ticket yet, check out the full details <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">here</a>.</p><p>Cya in a few weeks!</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why you can't write scenarios in Jam]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[there is a right way and a wrong way to do BDD, and the wrong way involves people using Gherkin to throw a specification over the wall at their development team]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/why-you-cant-write-scenarios-in-jam/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c8aea665500de00cc10f40e</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[Jam]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[BDD]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Process]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Wynne]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:27:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least, <a href="https://trello.com/c/PRkXknAo/37-edit-features-and-documents">not yet</a>.</p><p>A lot of people who are new to <a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">Jam</a> ask us: Why can't we write scenarios in the tool?</p><p>Here's why: We have a firm opinion that there is a right way and a wrong way to do BDD, and the wrong way involves people using Gherkin to throw a specification over the wall at their development team.</p><p>Yes, Jam's goal is to make BDD inclusive and accessible to everyone. We do want your business analyst to ❤️ ️️️living documentation after working with Jam. Ultimately, we do want them have the freedom to edit and even write new scenarios from within the tool.</p><p>But let's start with the basics.</p><h2 id="embrace-your-ignorance">Embrace your ignorance</h2><p>BDD is all about learning early. About <a href="https://dannorth.net/2010/08/30/introducing-deliberate-discovery/">deliberate discovery</a><em>.</em> About embracing your ignorance<em>.</em></p><p>If you want to learn early about what you don't know, a really good way to do that is to <a href="https://medium.com/@mattwynne/who-writes-the-cucumber-scenarios-6ca5f390c2fa">have the person with the most to learn, write the scenarios</a><em>.</em></p><p>That's why, instead of building a way for you to write scenarios, we prioritised developing a way for you to get feedback. Jam lets you publish your features so that your team can read and comment on them, inline, letting you iterate and reach agreement about what you're supposed to be building.</p><!--kg-card-begin: embed--><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card kg-card-hascaption"><iframe width="459" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gn7n6FFv-Yc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><figcaption>Comments in Cucumber Jam</figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-end: embed--><p>Like what you see? Jam is free for teams of up to three people, forever, and $10 / person / month for bigger teams. By paying for Jam you're supporting the future of the Cucumber open source project.</p><p>Sign up <a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CukenFest London asks: Jamie Knight and Mike Southgate]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>In the build up to our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> (April 4th-5th 2019), we've taken some time to chat to a few of our speakers about progressive software delivery techniques, BDD, and what people should expect to learn after attending their session.</p><p>Our guests this time are <a href="https://twitter.com/jamieknight?lang=en">Jamie</a></p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/cukenfest-london-asks-jamie-and-wookie/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c878cf19c781f00c0b1d4db</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cukenfest]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 09:55:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1064.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-1064.jpg" alt="CukenFest London asks: Jamie Knight and Mike Southgate"><p>In the build up to our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> (April 4th-5th 2019), we've taken some time to chat to a few of our speakers about progressive software delivery techniques, BDD, and what people should expect to learn after attending their session.</p><p>Our guests this time are <a href="https://twitter.com/jamieknight?lang=en">Jamie Knight</a> &amp; Lion and <a href="https://twitter.com/misterwookie">Mike Southgate</a> (aka, Wookie). Jamie and Wookie will deliver one of our keynote talks at CukenFest focusing on how they built a financial detection tool harnessing the power of BDD and autistic thinking. They have a great story to tell and we're excited for you to hear it. </p><p>Jamie and Wookie will present "Fighting crime and protecting vulnerable people using Gherkin, autism, and a half-built kit car." on April 4th at <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>.</p><h3 id="how-long-have-you-both-been-working-in-software-what-inspired-you-to-get-involved">How long have you both been working in software? What inspired you to get involved?</h3><p><br><strong>Jamie Knight</strong>: It’s been a little over 20 years since I started coding as kid. I started out coding visualisations for Winamp (!) but quickly found the web. The first 10 years where spent freelancing and the last ~10 have been spent working for the BBC in a range of roles from web developer to research engineer.</p><p>I’d been messing around with data processing projects for a number of years before we started ERMI - a tool for detecting financial crime - so I had some ideas for how we could achieve Mike’s ideas without needing to build a massive platform.</p><p><strong>Mike Southgate</strong>: Only since I started working on Ermi. Before that, I once made a light bulb flash on an Arduino and brutalised some HTML...</p><!--kg-card-begin: image--><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/mike-southgate.png" class="kg-image" alt="CukenFest London asks: Jamie Knight and Mike Southgate"><figcaption>Mike Southgate (AKA, Wookie)</figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-end: image--><p> The inspiration to get involved with ERMI came from trying to spend a fortunate on external tools whilst working at financial services firms. To process a really simple payment might require 8 systems, and each one can cost £100k+, we figured there must be a better way. </p><h3 id="how-did-you-both-meet-and-start-working-together">How did you both meet and start working together? </h3><p><strong>Jamie</strong>: We shared a client many many years ago. I did the nerdy stuff and Mike was doing legal / supplier stuff. We worked together on other projects before this project on things like engine rebuilds / kit cars / tiling kitchens / building decking.<br></p><p><strong>Mike</strong>: Yeah, we became friends over a roast dinner explaining nuclear reactors to the client, I think. </p><h3 id="when-building-ermi-how-did-you-harness-the-strengths-of-autistic-thinking">When building ERMI, how did you harness the strengths of autistic thinking? </h3><p><br><strong>Jamie</strong>: From the outset ermi had to be sustainable from a development, maintenance and quality perspective. Being autistic, I don’t have much energy. Ermi is focused on getting the most user value out of the energy I have and that has driven the design of the tool.  This has pushed us towards stateless systems, containerisation and a focus on repeatability. We have avoided time-sinks like custom user interfaces and web services. We have found clients prefer getting a file anyway. They don’t want yet <em>another</em> thing to log into.<br>While driven by our need to focus our limited energy, it’s made lots of other things easier. Scaling, security, deployment all benefit from a simple approach.<br></p><p><strong>Mike</strong>: It's probably fair to say that the solution that Jamie came up with is the epitome of autistic thinking. The current process that was there was stupid, how can we make it a bit better? By cutting out all of the unnecessary "features" we've managed to make a lightweight tool that achieves the same sort of result. Its either autistic thinking or "bloody mental"</p><h3 id="what-positive-outcomes-do-you-see-when-practising-bdd">What positive outcomes do you see when practising BDD? </h3><p><strong>Jamie</strong>: From an engineering perspective the BDD approach has given us the ability to move quickly and have confidence when we make changes. We have kept the ERMI codebase very lean because we have been able to refactor often. The feature files and Cucumber JS step files tend to outlive implementation details.<br>The BDD approach also gives us clean separation of requirements from the method of implementation. We use the same BDD feature files to apply the same end-to-end tests to multiple levels of the tool. The tests can run against a local branch, a built container, or our entire platform. Whatever form ERMI takes in the future we will be able to use the BDD feature files to validate it.</p><!--kg-card-begin: image--><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/jamie-knight.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="CukenFest London asks: Jamie Knight and Mike Southgate"><figcaption>Jamie Knight and Lion</figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-end: image--><p><strong>Mike</strong>: From the end user perspective, being able to very clearly define what behaviours I want from the tool have made things easier. I don't have a back and forth with Jamie over what a rule needs to do, its clearly defined and readable by both of us. </p><p>Because of the way we use Gherkin to define the rules, they are also readable by our end clients , which saves a lot of time in explaining them. Some of our clients currently have chunks of our original Gherkin in their policies and procedures, as they are so easily readable. </p><h3 id="what-do-you-think-are-the-biggest-challenges-that-organisations-face-in-software-development">What do you think are the biggest challenges that organisations face in software development?</h3><p><strong>Jamie</strong>: I can't speak much for the wider industry, but for us our biggest challenge is deciding what we build and what we pass on. We have taken some pretty tough decisions and left money on the table more than once in order to preserve our focus on being lightweight, affordable and flexible.</p><p><strong>Mike</strong>: Speaking purely from the perspective of banks at the moment, the move towards Open Banking an inter connectivity of  different services, as well as EU mandated rules around items such as security and accessibility, I think the biggest challenge is going to be making sure your code is good enough to be exposed to the outside world. Making something work internally is one thing, making it work internally with all of your legacy systems, and be able to be accessed by third parties with no security risks is a much bigger task. </p><p>Thanks for speaking to us, you two!</p><p>Read up on Jamie and Wookie's talk and see the whole line-up on the <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London website</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Jam: Unleash the joy of BDD]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The Cucumber team are releasing a new product today: <a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">Jam</a>.</p><p>Jam gives you the platform to succeed with BDD: a single source of truth that empowers the whole team. It's a user-friendly space to collaborate as your specifications evolve, wired up to your source control system so they’re always</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/jam-released-today/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c8771e89c781f00c0b1d482</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[Jam]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Wynne]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 13:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cucumber-2017-131.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cucumber-2017-131.jpg" alt="Jam: Unleash the joy of BDD"><p>The Cucumber team are releasing a new product today: <a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">Jam</a>.</p><p>Jam gives you the platform to succeed with BDD: a single source of truth that empowers the whole team. It's a user-friendly space to collaborate as your specifications evolve, wired up to your source control system so they’re always right up to date with your code.</p><p>Our goal with Jam is to bring the joy of Behaviour-Driven Development (BDD) to every software team on the planet. We know what a creative, inclusive, effective and downright fun way this is to build software, and we want to give everyone a chance to experience that.</p><p><a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">Sign up for Jam</a>.</p><h2 id="why-we-built-this-thing">Why we built this thing</h2><p>BDD is revolutionising the way people build software together.</p><p>As we get out and <a href="https://cucumber.io/training">help organisations</a> to adopt these practices, we’ve seen the need for something that compliments the world-beating open source tools we’ve already built.</p><p>BDD involves a paradigm shift in people’s behaviour, so we need to make that whole experience delightful for everyone, not just the developers and testers. Jam’s transparency keeps the relationship between product and engineering strong and collaborative, long after the feature files have gone into source control.</p><h2 id="a-little-history">A little history</h2><p>We’ve been working on different solutions to this problem for a long time. It started when the team behind the original BDD tool RSpec needed somewhere to <a href="http://relishapp.com/rspec">publish their feature files</a> as documentation, so we created Relish. Then we experimented with an <a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/2014/01/25/a-sneak-peek-at-cucumber-pro">early prototype of <em>Cucumber Pro</em></a><em>,</em><a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/2014/01/25/a-sneak-peek-at-cucumber-pro"> with collaborative editing</a>. We <a href="https://www.betonyourself.com/podcast/episode-16-matt-wynne">learned a lot</a> from that experiment, but ultimately decided to take a step back and start over.</p><p>Starting over and rebuilding Cucumber Pro from scratch helped us develop something solid that we’ve been proudly beta testing with hundreds of users from tiny start-ups to humongous financial services corporations. One of the significant things we learned from this testing was that the name didn’t work: Too many people assumed Cucumber Pro was just a “better cucumber”.</p><h2 id="jam">Jam</h2><p>The new name Jam sets the product aside as something completely different, but complementary to, the Cucumber open source tool. We like to think it reflects the playful spirit of collaboration that all BDD practitioners know and love.</p><p>We founded our company <a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/2014/04/16/cucumber-limited">to keep the open source ecosystem around Cucumber and BDD alive and healthy</a>. Having a commercial product that brings in recurring revenue is an important piece of the puzzle in creating that sustainable ecosystem.</p><p>We hope you’re as excited about tasting Jam as we are! <a href="https://cucumber.io/jam">Get Jam for your team here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Seb Rose on BDD, Cucumber, Cyber-Dojo, and Testers in Code Reviews]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><em>Join us in London on April 2nd-3rd for our public BDD Kickstart class taking place just before <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest</a>. This two-day class led by Jon Jagger explores all the technical and non-technical skills needed to apply BDD in your organisation to deliver less buggy software. <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">Learn more</a></em></p><p>This blog post is</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/seb-rose-on-bdd-cucumber-cyber-dojo-and-testers-in-code-reviews/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c80f0d89c781f00c0b1d39f</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 11:56:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/seb-rose-picture.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/seb-rose-picture.jpg" alt="Seb Rose on BDD, Cucumber, Cyber-Dojo, and Testers in Code Reviews"><p><em>Join us in London on April 2nd-3rd for our public BDD Kickstart class taking place just before <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest</a>. This two-day class led by Jon Jagger explores all the technical and non-technical skills needed to apply BDD in your organisation to deliver less buggy software. <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">Learn more</a></em></p><p>This blog post is the transcript of a conversation between our very own Seb Rose and InfoQ's Shane Hastie. The pair cover how Seb sees three central practices of BDD, his thoughts on including testers in code reviews, but he starts with why he thinks "passion" isn't a trait he looks for in colleagues.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Good day, folks! This is Shane Hastie for the <a href="https://www.infoq.com/engineering-culture-podcast/">InfoQ Engineering Culture Podcast</a>. I’m at the Agile 2018 Conference and privileged to sit down with Seb Rose. Seb, you are one of the founders of Cucumber Limited and you describe yourself as the dispassionate developer. Tell us a little bit more.</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	I started seeing the word ‘passionate’ kick off in job adverts, maybe 10-15 years ago. This is a conversation without pictures, so you can’t see either of our great beards, but I’ve been around for a while and I just didn’t understand why ‘passionate’ was being used. I feel that people that get passionate are often people that are less rational. I know that that might offend some folks, but I don’t want passion in the workplace. What I want is people to be considerate, I want people to be diligent, I want people to be involved, but the word ‘passionate’ doesn’t imply any of those things to me. So, a number of years ago, I did a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PechaKucha">pecha kucha</a> at an XP Conference called ‘Are you passionate?’ where I suggested that passion wasn’t what we really were looking for and since then, various people picked up on it and I’ve much amplified it by <a href="https://twitter.com/sebrose">my Twitter description</a> where I say I am dispassionate developer.</p><!--kg-card-begin: embed--><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="100%" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F562805796&show_artwork=true"></iframe></figure><!--kg-card-end: embed--><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	You’re also known for your work on Behaviour-Driven Development. You want to tell us a little about what’s happening there?</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	I came across FIT and FitNesse during my tenure at IBM. I’ve spent most of my life as a freelancer, but I’ve done a couple of stints with large corporations, IBM being one of them and Amazon being another. It’s true to say that FIT and FitNesse really wasn’t picked by my colleagues at IBM, but I got really interested in it. Subsequent to that, I worked for an insurance company and by that time, I was beginning to tinker with Cucumber. In those days, Cucumber was still just a Ruby project. I wasn’t working in Ruby and when <a href="https://twitter.com/aslak_hellesoy">Aslak</a> released the Cucumber for the Java version – Cucumber JVM – I just thought, “Wow, this is amazing. Let me have a go at this,” and actually, within the context of the insurance company that I was working at, we had an absolute perfect-fit project, where we working with actuaries and business people. </p><p>The whole project was around repricing insurance. There was very little technical stuff going on, but there was a change of data, there was a change of business rules, so the discussion, the Cucumber business-readable specification was just an amazing tool. As a side effect of that, we then also decreased the testing cycle from about a week and a half to around an hour and that was a game change for them. In the repricing situation they were in, they were fairly sure that the whole market was going to be moving on a daily basis and they wanted to be very flexible in repricing. Obviously, a three-week approval cycle for repricing is not going to give you very much flexibility, whereas a one-hour testing cycle was just what they wanted. </p><p>That really sold me on the power of Gherkin to Cucumber to describe technical, deep business rules in a business-readable language and from there, I’ve engaged with Aslak in online communication. His partner in crime, <a href="https://twitter.com/mattwynne">Matt Wynne</a>, actually also lives in Scotland – on the other side of Scotland from me, but Scotland’s not that big a country. So, we met up after a conference in Edinburgh. I started working with Matt, I drank the Kool-Aid, he taught me everything that he was prepared to teach me about BDD and how Cucumber helps roll out the implementation of BDD and the rest is history.</p><p>Matt, Aslak and <a href="https://twitter.com/jbpros">Julien Biezemans</a> founded Cucumber Limited in 2013 and invited <a href="https://twitter.com/tooky">Steve Tooke</a> and myself to become co-owners a couple of years later. I’ve been running the training arm of Cucumber Limited for the past three years. I’ve developed training material using experiential techniques which I’ve learnt from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerald_Weinberg">Gerry Weinberg</a> and <a href="http://bowperson.com/">Sharon Bowman</a>. I do a lot of conference speaking. Basically, I guess I am a proselytizer for BDD as a collaboration tool. I joined Matt and Aslak and the rest of the team in <a href="https://cucumber.io/blog/2014/03/03/the-worlds-most-misunderstood-collaboration-tool">trying to dissuade</a> people from using Cucumber purely as a test automation tool.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Tell us a bit more about using Cucumber as a collaboration tool.</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	Behaviour-driven development has been historically hard to describe. There is a nice quote that Matt Wynne put into the first Cucumber book, which is a sentence which describes Cucumber as a combination of conversation, concrete examples and automated tests, but in many environments, I find that it’s not immediately understandable to the people that read it. Dan North, who created BDD, has also tried to come up with some definitions. They’re also quite hard to parse and don’t immediately talk to the people who really need a definition. </p><p>Based on discussions with Liz Keogh and while Gaspar Nagy and I were writing a book called ‘<a href="http://bddbooks.com">Discovery</a>’, we created a small pictographic which shows BDD as being made up of three distinct practices which we’ve called <em>Discovery</em>, <em>Formulation</em> and <em>Automation</em>. Cucumber only kicks in at the Automation space. However, what we show in the pictographic is that you have to start with Discovery. </p><!--kg-card-begin: image--><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/IMG_0851.PNG" class="kg-image" alt="Seb Rose on BDD, Cucumber, Cyber-Dojo, and Testers in Code Reviews"></figure><!--kg-card-end: image--><p>Discovery is the practice that you need to start with and that’s about communication between the business and the delivery team. The delivery team will be made up of predominantly developers and testers, but not excluding designers, UX, security, performance, whatever it might be. During the Discovery phase, we have face-to-face communication between the business stakeholders and the delivery team. That conversation is targeted at making sure that everyone understands what’s being asked and why it’s being asked. It gives us a chance to use concrete examples to make sure that those requirements, those business rules that are being asked to be implemented are defined unambiguously because our experience is that business rules, acceptance criteria, requirements are rife with ambiguities and potential for misinterpretation. This is the Discovery phase. At the end of this Discovery phase, we expect to have the business rules clarified by one or more concrete examples to make sure that they can’t be misinterpreted.</p><p>Then with tools such as FIT and FitNesse and Cucumber, you would take those concrete examples and convert them into a format that is still precise, still unambiguous, but is readable by non-technical members of the team – not just testers, not just developers, but also business people, customers etc. That format within the Cucumber ecosystem is called ‘Gherkin’ and people will be familiar with the given-when-then keywords of Gherkin. Gherkin is by no means the only way of doing it. There are many other tools and formats that allow you to do this, but the critical thing is that it must be concrete, unambiguous examples documented in business language so that business people can give you feedback on them. That’s the Formulation phase.</p><p>Then, the third practice is Automation where the concrete examples are effectively wired up into the system that you’re building. In the recommended approaches, we would suggest that you go through the discovery practice on a story, take those concrete examples and formulate them as Gherkin, then automate those concrete examples before anyone starts writing the code to implement those features. What you’ve got is Behaviour-Driven Development. </p><p>In Discovery you’ve discussed the behaviour, in Formulation you have captured it as business-readable documentation and in Automation you are now driving the development of the system by a failing specification. Some people might want to call them ‘acceptance tests’. I’m easy on terminology here. Those are the three practices that form BDD. Cucumber comes in at the end where it reads the Gherkin and wires it up to the system that you’re building.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	And that then leads nicely into the technical approaches of TDD.</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	Exactly.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	We’re doing TDD at the middle level.</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	Yes, and one of the questions that we often get asked is, “Does BDD replace TDD?” It’s worth stating for the record in absolute terms that no. BDD supplements TDD. You go from a BDD-failing specification to a much more detailed, low-level programmer facing tests that will drive out the tiny increments in behaviour that you would expect from a TDD approach.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Thank you for that! Another thing that you’re known for is your work on the <a href="http://cyber-dojo.org">Cyber-Dojo</a>. Tell us a bit about that.</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	I am part of the <a href="http://cyber-dojo.org">Cyber-Dojo</a> organisation. It’s an open-source project that was founded and created by a man called <a href="https://twitter.com/jonjagger?lang=en">Jon Jagger</a>, a very close colleague and friend of mine in the UK, and he created it to help him with his training of teams to practice programming and Test-Driven Development specifically. I encourage anyone listening who is in any way interested in the development of software to go and take a look at cyber-dojo.org. What it does is it provides dozens of online development environments that you can access with no install and no cost, which means that if you want to practice with people writing Swift or C++ or Java, press a button and you’re in a very lightweight IDE.</p><p>It also ships with dozens of Katas that you can practice and it has some wonderful training tools which provide you multiple avatars or multiple groups working on the same problem at the same time and some brilliant tools that allow you to compare different group approaches to solving the same problem. It’s a wonderful tool. It’s free to use for individuals. We do ask for businesses that use it internally for launching or training their teams to pay a small license fee. 100% of the license fees go to buying Raspberry Pis for schools in developing countries. It’s a win-win all the way down. It’s here to help your teams practice and the money generated goes towards helping people in more disadvantages places get into the IT space.</p><blockquote>On including testers in code reviews: "We’re not asking people who are not experienced in a particular programming language to try and work out whether the semicolon is in the right place...What we’re trying to do is ensure that the code itself is written in a way that anyone can read and understand the flow in the structure."</blockquote><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Easy enough to find! At the conference, you’ve given a couple of talks. The one I would like to explore initially is the certification. What’s the state of certification and what are your thoughts there?</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	The talk I gave was on the "IEEE’s future of Agile track" and I wanted to explore the domain of certification because it’s become a huge industry within the Agile space. I had a particular interest because in Cucumber, as the training manager, I have recently being trying to enlarge the number of people that can deliver our training material without decreasing its value or exposing us to reputational risk. Certification is one of those things that I was interested in. </p><p>At the same time, a lot of the people that I respect within the Agile community believe that the certification that is available in the Agile space is not great, that a lot of it is paying money for a certificate that you then have to revalidate. It’s just a treadmill of making money out of people. The talk that I gave was just a 30-minute talk and I looked at the four different certifications that I reviewed while trying to work out how to pitch a Cucumber formal approval process. They included the PVG Certificate that you have to get if you want to work with children. That stands for ‘Protecting Vulnerable Groups’. I looked at Chainsaw Certification because although it may seem that software and chainsaws are quite dissimilar, you can do a lot of damage with software and a bad code or a bad Scrum master could really chop up a team like you could chop up a tree. I looked at a couple of other certifications, too. </p><p>The talk was basically looking at the proprieties of these different certifications or approval schemes. What do they guarantee? How do they help the people doing the certification get value? How do they help the people obtaining the certification get value? How do they help the people who use the certification as some sort of signal or differentiator build that trust in those people that hold certificates? A fair amount to get through in half an hour and I’m not sure I did it justice, but as part of the process within Cucumber, we came up with something that we call ‘the Cucumber-Approved Trainer scheme’ and that word, ‘approved’, was put in possibly a little bit thoughtlessly. We actually did it because we liked the acronym that it built. We now have a body of CATs and we’re trying to herd the cats.</p><p>The Cucumber-Approved Trainer Program is quite onerous because one of the things that we found in the certification that we trusted was that it wasn’t a one or two-day course with a multiple-choice question at the end of it. It was something that had a prolonged interaction between the provider of the certification and the person gaining certification. Our program requires people first off to go through a phone or online interview to try and make sure that they’ve got the right background, right motivation, that we can communicate with them and that they can articulate things in a way that’s understandable. Then, we go through three interactions – training and engagement – which we stole entirely, lock, stock and barrel, from the Chainsaw Certification, and they call it “See it, do it, nail it”. </p><p>In the ‘See it’ phase, you are a participant in a training class which means that you get to understand the interactions, you get to see how a qualified and experienced trainer works with the cohort. Then, in ‘Do it’, you participate in delivering it, but in conjunction with another qualified trainer and in the third, ‘Nail it’, you deliver that training material, being observed. In all parts of this process, the people you’re working with gather feedback, interact with you to try and ensure that we pick up on any weaknesses, that you can focus on areas that you want to improve in. </p><p>There’s no guarantee that you’ll ever make it through the ‘See it, Do it, Nail it’. We may feel and you may feel that you need to go through the ‘Nail it’ a couple of times before you’re happy. At that point, you get the badge, you go on the website as being an approved trainer, you can deliver our training material and contribute to the evolution of it and join the community of CATS and get information from there.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Another talk that you gave encouraged the inclusion of testers in code reviews. Surely, that’s just logical today?!</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	I would have thought it was logical, but you don’t see it very often. Despite the fact that Agile is in mainstream – certainly has crossed the chasm – I still see a proliferation of organisations where cross-functional team is a name only. The testers still report to different management structures, they might sit with the team, but they still operate on different columns of the Kanban board and it still gets chopped over the edge. We see stories that are so large that testers may not have a huge number of things to work with during much of the iteration and on the night before the end of the iteration, all the stories get delivered and so, then there’s a panic. </p><p>There are a lot of dysfunctions in many organisations that are adopting Agile and I very rarely see testers interacting with the code at any level. There may be communication and discussion between the test and the development people, but actually, going in and participating in code review… I hardly ever see it. We should qualify this by the fact that I work as a <a href="http://cucumber.io/training">trainer and coach for Cucumber Limited</a> and typically, we don’t get invited into places where everything’s peachy. I probably have a kind of biased or distorted view of the industry, but having spoken to a lot of people here today – and there were 50 or 60 people in my talk the day before yesterday – I don’t think that my viewpoint if wildly off from the norm of what people experience.</p><!--kg-card-begin: image--><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-0938.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Seb Rose on BDD, Cucumber, Cyber-Dojo, and Testers in Code Reviews"></figure><!--kg-card-end: image--><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	For somebody who wants to encourage that sort of, “Let’s move to a more cross-functional team, let’s engage our testers…” One of the things I’ve heard from a few testers is, “I don’t even want to read the code. I don’t understand that stuff.” How do we bridge those gaps?</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	The great thing about trying to get testers involved in code reviews is not that they’re reviewing the code. We’re not asking people who are not experienced in a particular programming language to try and work out whether the semicolon is in the right place or whether this is an efficient algorithm. What we’re trying to do is ensure that the code itself is written in a way that anyone can read and understand the flow in the structure. That should include having method and variable names that echo concepts from the domain.</p><p>This is something that, for instance, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Clean-Code-Handbook-Software-Craftsmanship/dp/0132350882">Bob Martin</a> has talked about a lot in his books about clean code. It’s about doing literate programming, literate in the sense that we are reflecting domain concepts all the way through the lifecycle of software, from specification through to delivery. If you write your programmer tests with names that specify what the behaviour is that they are asserting or verifying, if you write your method names with terms from the business domain that describe what functionality or behaviour they’re offering, if you give variable names that talk about the domain objects that are being passed around, now you can involve technical-literate, business-literate testers in that space and they can then begin to think about, “Is this an approach that I can see matching the requirements that I have heard the business people ask for?” This then encourages discussion. </p><p>It also helps because the testers can now see what programmer tests are being written and actually may take a view of where is there a gap. Are there some tests that the programmers have missed? Are there errors where there’s clearly risk that I should do more exploration in? It gives everybody information. It gives the programmers information about, “I’ll be writing in a literate way that is going to be understandable by the next programmer team that has to pick up this product.” It gives the testers information about, “What testing have the developers already considered?” This allows lots of different areas of cross-skilling, up-skilling and risk-management around, “Where should we focus our exploratory efforts?”</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Thanks very much for taking the time to talk to us! If people want to reach out and carry on the conversation, where do they find you?</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	Twitter is always a good place. My name is Seb Rose, my Twitter handle is <a href="https://twitter.com/sebrose">@sebrose</a>, my <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebrose">LinkedIn handle is Seb Rose</a> and I'm seb@cucumber.io.</p><p><strong>Shane Hastie</strong>:	Thank you very much!</p><p><strong>Seb Rose</strong>:	Thank you!</p><p><em>Join us in London on April 2nd-3rd for our public <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">BDD Kickstart class</a> with Jon Jagger. This is a two-day class which explores all the technical and non-technical skills needed to apply BDD in your organisation to build less buggy software. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CukenFest London Asks:  Alex Schladebeck]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[We sat down with Alex Schladebeck, keynote of CukenFest London 2019, about BDD, software quality, and the importance of the whole team approach. ]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/cukenfest-london-asks-alex-schladebeck/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c7d4cf8c0121300c04281b0</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cukenfest]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 10:38:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/alex-cukenfest.png" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/alex-cukenfest.png" alt="CukenFest London Asks:  Alex Schladebeck"><p>In the build up to our annual Behaviour-Driven Development conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a> (April 4th-5th 2019), we've taken some time to chat to a few of our speakers about progressive software delivery techniques, BDD, and what people should expect to learn after attending their session. </p><p>This time we sat down with Alex Schladebeck, one of our keynote speakers. Alex is an agile tester consultant and linguist, well known in Agile and Testing circles as an excellent speaker and communicator. It was my colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/SalFreudenberg">Sal Freudenberg</a> who first suggested Alex as a keynote speaker for CukenFest, arguing that Alex cares as deeply about software quality as our audience does. So who better to deliver a keynote on the importance of the whole-team approach to software quality.</p><p>Alex will present "Whole Team Quality: In the same boat or up the creek?" on April 4th at <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>. </p><p></p><h3 id="how-long-have-you-been-working-in-software-what-inspired-you-to-get-involved">How long have you been working in software? What inspired you to get involved?</h3><p>I’ve been working in software since 2005. I joined an IT company as a translator, but my role very quickly moved into much more testing and asking questions. I love learning, so I really thrived in an environment where everything was new. Once I realised I was also good at parts of it, I think that became my inspiration to remain involved. I love working with people to solve problems. And I love talking about what I’ve learned with others. I’m very lucky that my job lets me do that.</p><p></p><h3 id="what-do-you-think-are-the-biggest-challenges-that-organisations-face-in-software-development">What do you think are the biggest challenges that organisations face in software development?</h3><p>It’s gonna sound cheesy – but it’s always about the people! People working together to discover needs, solve problems and make technology do the things they want it to. To be more concrete, I think that the big challenges at the moment are making sure that people can craft their life and job in an individual way that works for their context, and getting the right balance between working on projects and preparing for the future (learning and experimenting in new areas).</p><p></p><blockquote>Quality isn’t visible. We don’t see the tangible effects of testing. It’s like oxygen. You can’t see it but you’d really miss it if it wasn’t there.</blockquote><p></p><h3 id="how-do-you-see-the-role-of-a-tester-in-2019">How do you see the role of a tester in 2019? </h3><p>Looking back at over 10 years of experience (wow, I feel old!), I think that testers are finally being recognised for their importance and the good work they do. I meet more and more people who wouldn’t want to be in a project without one and who respect the opinions and experience of testers. There are still opinion pieces and articles about why testing is dead and why we don’t need testers any more. Ironically, these are almost never written by people who know what testers do. If I’m being cheeky, I can say it’s fairly easy for a developer who doesn’t understand the importance of testing to claim that it’s not necessary!</p><p>Our role remains what it has always been, I think. Be involved in the team, embed ourselves in the processes, ask questions, deliver relevant and timely information, experiment and explore. All that with the aim of helping and enabling the team to better quality. The details look different in every project, but for me, that’s the gist.</p><p></p><h3 id="what-common-anti-patterns-do-you-see-software-delivery-teams-doing">What common anti-patterns do you see software delivery teams doing?</h3><p>For me the classics that I keep an eye out for (and usually notice) are that we think too big, too much and too easy! We take on too much work in progress, we’re bad at asking what the smallest valuable increment could really be, we think things will be a lot quicker and easier than they are, and we underestimate what can go wrong. All of these things affect the quality.</p><p></p><h3 id="why-do-you-think-quality-is-often-left-to-the-testers">Why do you think "quality" is often left to the testers? </h3><p>This actually stumped me for a bit. It’s a good question. That is often the status quo – but as to why?...</p><p>I think there could be a few reasons.</p><p>Humans tend to be result driven. When something is implemented, it can feel like I’m done. We know that’s not true, but I can empathise with the sentiment.</p><p>Quality isn’t visible. We don’t see the tangible effects of testing. It’s like oxygen. You can’t see it but you’d really miss it if it wasn’t there. (Sure, we can count bug reports as a visible thing, but I sincerely doubt whether that’s helpful).</p><p>Many teams have gotten away with their quality strategy relying on quick hot fixes, good luck and perhaps good review techniques. If quality doesn’t feel like a risk, it’s easier to ignore.</p><p></p><h3 id="what-are-some-tricks-for-changing-the-mindset-of-the-whole-team-to-think-about-quality">What are some tricks for changing the mindset of the whole team to think about quality? </h3><p>I have a whole keynote about this with <a href="https://twitter.com/huibschoots">Huib Schoots</a> 😊 The first step is to embed yourself in everything the team does. Understand the people, the processes, the product/project. Then you can start to use your great tester skills to ask questions, make suggestions (I’m going to mention biscuit-driven-development here because biscuits help with this!) and ask for help. Testers have so many things in their toolbox to get teams on board to improve quality, but we don’t often realise what they are. Introducing exploratory testing either in pairs or in mobs can help to inspire and intrigue the whole team for example. Another great tip is to just assume that you have the authority to change things. I like to say that the only thing a tester should assume is responsibility. And finally, just working with the team. Pairing with developers, asking for support – those are great ways of becoming a respected team member that people want to help and listen to.</p><p>Thanks for chatting with us Alex!</p><p>Read up on Alex's talk and the whole line-up on the <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London website</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hello to our new blog! 👋]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="welcome-welcome-">Welcome! Welcome! </h2><p>Take a look around and make yourself at home. This is the new face of the Cucumber blog. </p><p>As part of a bigger project, we've begun to migrate our site off of Jekyll, running on Heroku, to Squarespace. The first wave of changes were to the <a href="https://cucumber.io/">homepage</a> as</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/the-new-face-of-cucumbers-blog/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c7a2170b1aca800ccd63b59</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jayson Smith]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 06:59:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1536560035542-1326fab3a507?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="welcome-welcome-">Welcome! Welcome! </h2><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1536560035542-1326fab3a507?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&q=80&fm=jpg&crop=entropy&cs=tinysrgb&w=1080&fit=max&ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Hello to our new blog! 👋"><p>Take a look around and make yourself at home. This is the new face of the Cucumber blog. </p><p>As part of a bigger project, we've begun to migrate our site off of Jekyll, running on Heroku, to Squarespace. The first wave of changes were to the <a href="https://cucumber.io/">homepage</a> as well as <a href="https://cucumber.io/events">events</a>, so if you've noticed a change, now you know why!</p><p>On and off over the past month, I've been working on the second wave of changes: migrating our blog. The words you're reading now are hosted on the <a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost</a> platform and we're quite happy with this new change. Ghost is an open source project, have a nice web editor for posts (which is great if you don't want to write Markdown, though you can do that in the editor too if you'd like), options to self-host or have them do it, and they have a support team that's been a pleasure to work with. Check them out if you're unfamiliar.</p><p>One feature I'd like to draw your attention to is the search in the upper right-hand corner. If you click on the magnifying glass, you'll be presented with a search field as well as all of our tags and authors to make searching and filtering easy. If you're interested in a particular topic, clicking on its tag will take you to a page with all the posts with that tag. If you want to go through all of our podcasts, <a href="https://cucumber.io/tag/podcast">there's a tag for that.</a></p><p>Let us know what you think. If there are things that aren't working quite right, let us know in a comment below.</p><h3 id="one-last-thing">One last thing</h3><p>Before we wrap up, we'd like to extend an offer to all who may be interested: <strong>Write for us!</strong> If you've already written with us, we encourage you to come and write some more and if you're new, welcome. We're open to all sorts of topics not strictly ones about Cucumber/BDD. Is there a process or a neat trick you've got to make folk's lives easier in their testing/development work? Perhaps you've got a story about your team's journey and embrace of BDD you'd like to share?</p><p>For folks who had written for us before, head over to our <a href="https://cucumber.io/ghost/">admin page</a> to do a password reset and reactivate your accounts. If you have any trouble, let myself or someone else on the team know.</p><p>For folks who are new to the Cucumber writers team, send an email to blog@cucumber.io and let us know what you'd like to write about. We'll get you set up with an account and you can get going.</p><p>Thanks, welcome, and we hope you enjoy our new digs!</p><p>-- Jayson</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CukenFest London Asks: Marit van Dijk]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>In the build up to our annual BDD conference, CukenFest London, we've spoken to a few of our speakers about software development, BDD, and their upcoming session in April.</p>
<p>Our first interview is with <a href="https://twitter.com/MaritvanDijk77">Marit van Dijk</a>. Marit is a core contributer to the Cucumber OSS and a software and</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/cukenfest-london-asks-marit-van-dijk/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c780301b1aca800ccd63b42</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cukenfest]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-2.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/03/Cukenfest-2018-2.jpg" alt="CukenFest London Asks: Marit van Dijk"><p>In the build up to our annual BDD conference, CukenFest London, we've spoken to a few of our speakers about software development, BDD, and their upcoming session in April.</p>
<p>Our first interview is with <a href="https://twitter.com/MaritvanDijk77">Marit van Dijk</a>. Marit is a core contributer to the Cucumber OSS and a software and test engineer at <a href="https://bol.com">bol.com</a>. Marit will speak at CukenFest London on &quot;Collaborating on Open Source&quot;. You can read more about her talk and others <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io#talks">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>How long have you been working in software? What inspired you to be involved?</strong></p>
<p>I've been working in software development for about 15 years. In that time I've had many different roles in different companies. My roles have included information analysis, project management and test automation engineer. Over the years, I've gradually moved into more technical roles. At the moment I do test automation and software development.</p>
<p><strong>What common anti-patterns do you see software delivery teams making?</strong></p>
<p>The main challenge I have noticed in my career, is making sure to build the right thing and focus on the things that are important to your product or client. It can be quite hard to really understand your domain, and to translate that to software that provides the most value to the users.<br>
At the same time, making sure to build it right can be quite a challenge. Especially when there is a high focus on delivering features and maybe not enough time to lower technical debt.</p>
<p><strong>What drove you to first start contributing to an OSS project?</strong></p>
<p>Due to a reorganisation at the company I was working for, I had to relearn (Java) programming. I started doing coding challenges, but after a while I wanted to work on an actual project and maybe do something useful. After switching employers, I started using Cucumber and really liked it, so I figured I'd see if I could contribute. When I first started, everyone was very helpful and welcoming - which is a big part of why I stayed so active. I love the feeling of being part of a community, doing things that help other people. And I've also learned lots of different things that are helpful in my day job.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What I like about open source is that it offers the opportunity to actually help improve the tools we all use at work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>If you were to give one piece of advice to someone willing to contribute to OSS, what would it?</strong></p>
<p>As I will discuss in my talk, there are many, many different ways to contribute to OSS. You don't have to be a programmer, and it doesn't have to take a lot of time to make things just a little bit better. Everyone has something to offer to open source, based on their particular skill set. If you are looking for ways to contribute, I hope my talk will give you some ideas. And maybe we can get some people started during the open space?</p>
<p><strong>What are you working on at the moment in the Cucumber OSS?</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes I work Cucumber-jvm, but mainly I work on the documentation. There are plenty of things we would like to add and improve; unfortunately my time is limited. In addition, I'm active on the Cucumber Slack and try to help people who have questions.</p>
<p><strong>What excites you about the future of OSS?</strong></p>
<p>What I like about open source is that it offers the opportunity to actually help improve the tools we all use at work. If you find a bug or want an additional feature, you can build it. But mainly, I love the community around open source, of people who want to make things just a little bit better, a little bit at a time. What I love most, is people who stop by to contribute from fixing typos or dead links, or doing reviews, to building entire new features. It makes me really happy.</p>
<p><strong>What are you most looking forward to at CukenFest London?</strong></p>
<p>The people! Last year I got to meet a bunch of people I'd previously only collaborated with online. This year I look forward to seeing them again, and meeting new people! (And of course, if I can get anyone interested in collaborating with us, that would be a big bonus).</p>
<p>Join Marit and 120 other BDD enthusiasts for <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[BDD with Cucumber Webinar]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of teams are benefitting from BDD (Behaviour-Driven Development). This 20-minute talk will familiarise you with what BDD is and isn’t so you can decide if it’s right for your team. Ryan will stick around to take questions about BDD, Cucumber, and transformative agile practices.</p>
<p>Ryan Marsh is</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/bdd-with-cucumber/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c69f012a63cd100c1fb1a47</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/02/bdd-with-cucumber-webinar.png" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cucumber.io/content/images/2019/02/bdd-with-cucumber-webinar.png" alt="BDD with Cucumber Webinar"><p>Hundreds of teams are benefitting from BDD (Behaviour-Driven Development). This 20-minute talk will familiarise you with what BDD is and isn’t so you can decide if it’s right for your team. Ryan will stick around to take questions about BDD, Cucumber, and transformative agile practices.</p>
<p>Ryan Marsh is an agile coach, trainer, and hacker who works with enterprise software development teams to help them be their very best. Ryan believes enterprise software development can be fun, rewarding, and move at high speed no matter the industry. Ryan has helped technology teams supercharge their development at some of America’s most well-known companies. Ryan is a self-taught hacker with a varied background in technology. He is also US Army veteran. Ryan leverages this unique perspective to help teams reach their full potential.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/gpepeoHAN7g">Watch the recording on our YouTube channel.</a></p>
<p>Ryan will be teaching our two-day <a href="https://cucumber.io/events/2019/04/bdd-kickstart-london">BDD Kickstart class in London</a> on April 2nd-3rd just before our annual BDD conference, <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io">CukenFest London</a></p>
<h3 id="shownotes">Shownotes</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cucumber.io/support#slack">Join us on Slack</a> to discuss BDD and Cucumber in more detail.</li>
<li>We offer training and coaching services for ambitious teams who want to benefit from BDD and Cucumber. Check out our <a href="https://cucumber.io/training">training page</a> for more details.</li>
</ul>
<!-- Drip -->
<script type="text/javascript">
  var _dcq = _dcq || [];
  var _dcs = _dcs || {}; 
  _dcs.account = '7849462';
  
  (function() {
    var dc = document.createElement('script');
    dc.type = 'text/javascript'; dc.async = true; 
    dc.src = '//tag.getdrip.com/7849462.js';
    var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0];
    s.parentNode.insertBefore(dc, s);
  })();
</script>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Testing in DevOps - Cucumber Podcast]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/560429766&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe>
<p>This month on the podcast we speak to Janet Gregory and Lisa Crispin about testing in DevOps. The conversation covers the whole team approach and why testers are as important as ever.</p>
<p>Asking the questions from Cucumber is Matt Wynne, Sallyann Freudenberg, and Steve Tooke.</p>
<h3 id="shownotes">Show notes</h3>
<p>Janet &amp; Lisa's</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/testing-in-devops/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c69ef9ea63cd100c1fb1a3b</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1512851685250-bfa0aa982a1c?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/560429766&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe>
<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1512851685250-bfa0aa982a1c?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&q=80&fm=jpg&crop=entropy&cs=tinysrgb&w=1080&fit=max&ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Testing in DevOps - Cucumber Podcast"><p>This month on the podcast we speak to Janet Gregory and Lisa Crispin about testing in DevOps. The conversation covers the whole team approach and why testers are as important as ever.</p>
<p>Asking the questions from Cucumber is Matt Wynne, Sallyann Freudenberg, and Steve Tooke.</p>
<h3 id="shownotes">Show notes</h3>
<p>Janet &amp; Lisa's website - <a href="https://agiletester.ca/">Link</a></p>
<p>Agile Testing (Book) - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Agile-Testing-Practical-Guide-Testers/dp/0321534468/ref=sr_1_3?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1547738499&amp;sr=1-3&amp;keywords=agile+testing">Link</a></p>
<p>More Agile Testing (Book) - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/More-Agile-Testing-Addison-Wesley-Signature/dp/0321967054/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1547739142&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=more+agile+testing">Link</a></p>
<p>Agile Testing Essentials (Lisa and Janet's new online class) - <a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/agile-testing-essentials/9780134683287/">Link</a></p>
<p>On Twitter:</p>
<p>Janet Gregory <a href="https://twitter.com/janetgregoryca">@janetgregoryca</a><br>
Lisa Crispin <a href="https://twitter.com/lisacrispin">@lisacrispin</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/cucumberbdd">Cucumber on Twitter</a></p>
<p>You can also listen and download the podcast on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/cucumber-podcast-rss/id1078896635">iTunes</a>, <a href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=81999&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a> or wherever you get your podcasts.</p>
<p>Join us in our <a href="https://cucumber.io/support#slack">Slack channel</a> or on <a href="https://twitter.com/cucumberbdd">Twitter</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Domain Storytelling - Cucumber Podcast]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/543830436&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe>
<p>This month on the Cucumber Podcast we speak to Stefan Hofer about Domain Storytelling. Stefan describes Domain Storytelling as &quot;a workshop format which helps people have a conversation about their domain; the idea is that domain experts tell stories that explain how people and software systems work together.&quot;</p>]]></description>
      <link>https://cucumber.io/blog/domain-storytelling/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5c59a90da554ed00c06b4d08</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Theo England]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1475483768296-6163e08872a1?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" medium="image"/>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/543830436&color=%23ff5500&auto_play=false&hide_related=false&show_comments=true&show_user=true&show_reposts=false&show_teaser=true"></iframe>
<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1475483768296-6163e08872a1?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&q=80&fm=jpg&crop=entropy&cs=tinysrgb&w=1080&fit=max&ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Domain Storytelling - Cucumber Podcast"><p>This month on the Cucumber Podcast we speak to Stefan Hofer about Domain Storytelling. Stefan describes Domain Storytelling as &quot;a workshop format which helps people have a conversation about their domain; the idea is that domain experts tell stories that explain how people and software systems work together.&quot;</p>
<p>Although well known and celebrated in the Domain Driven Design community, Domain Storytelling is starting to be discovered by software teams wanting to find innovative ways to build shared understanding.</p>
<p>Asking the questions from Cucumber is Matt Wynne and Sallyann Freudenberg.</p>
<p><em>Shownotes:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.domainstorytelling.org/">Domain Storytelling</a></p>
<p>Find Context Boundaries with Domain Storytelling - Stefan Hofer and Henning Schwenter - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y1ykXnl6r7s">Link</a></p>
<p>CukenFest London - Our annual BDD conference happening on April 4th-5th 2019 - <a href="http://cukenfest.cucumber.io/">Link</a></p>
<p>The &quot;Swim&quot; System - <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/images/2/20/Swim_System_PNSQC_2007_Paper.pdf">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/hofstef">Stefan on Twitter</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/cucumberbdd">Cucumber on Twitter</a></p>
<p>You can also listen and download the podcast on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/cucumber-podcast-rss/id1078896635">iTunes</a>, <a href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=81999&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a> or wherever you get your podcasts.</p>
<p>Join us in our <a href="https://cucumber.io/support#slack">Slack channel</a> or on <a href="https://twitter.com/cucumberbdd">Twitter</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
